Fruit basket
Mobius uses indentation for block delimitation and it's done automatically when a line is added to the procedure.
For control structures like conditions and loops which can be nested in one another,
similar to how you add a statement to a specific line,
ensure the line is selected and click on the interested statement to add it in.
This video will also discuss the logic of basic nested control statements: nesting conditions within conditions and conditions within loops.
Loop nesting will be discussed next week.
Conditions can be nested within another condition block.
Its execution follows logic tree and can be used when we are expecting multiple states for the inputs and returning a different output for each condition.
For example,
suppose we have a basket of red apples,
green apples,
oranges and lemons.
We want to sort them separately into individual baskets.
We may start off the condition check by identifying whether the food is an apple.
If it is,
we check for its color.
If it is red,
we put it in the first basket.
If green,
in the second basket.
Otherwise,
if the fruit is an orange,
place in the third basket.
At this point,
if a fruit fails the check,
place it in the fourth basket.
That's for the lemons.
The block we had ended with earlier only checks for single fruit,
but what we want is to check an entire basket!
Essentially,
this sorting block should be run on every fruit in the basket.
To do this,
we will loop through the basket at one fruit at a time and run the check.
You will just be placing the condition block we have created earlier into a loop to do so.