{"video_file_name": "02_Fruit_basket_video", "display_name": "Fruit basket", "voice": "3"}
Mobius uses indentation for block
delimitation and it's done automatically
when a line is added to the procedure.
For control structures like conditions and loops which can be nested in one another,
similar to how you add a statement to a specific line,
ensure the line is selected and click on the
interested statement to add it in.
This video will also discuss the logic of
basic nested control statements:
nesting conditions within conditions and conditions within loops.
Loop nesting
will be discussed next week.
Conditions can be nested within another condition block.
Its execution follows logic tree
and can be used when we are expecting
multiple states for the inputs and
returning a different output for each
condition.
For example, suppose we have a
basket of red apples, green apples,
oranges and lemons.
We want to sort them separately into individual baskets.
We may start off the condition check by
identifying whether the food is an apple.
If it is, we check for its color.
If it is red, we put it in the first basket. If
green, in the second basket.
Otherwise, if the fruit is an orange, place in the third basket.
At this point, if a fruit fails the check,
place it in the fourth basket. That's
for the lemons.
The block we had ended with earlier only checks for single fruit,
but what we want is to check an entire basket!
Essentially, this sorting block should be
run on every fruit in the basket.
To do this, we will loop through the basket at
one fruit at a time and run the check.
You will just be placing the condition block we have created earlier into a loop to do so.